# Bastian T. Eichenberger

## Summary

I finished my Master of Science in Molecular Biology at the age of 19 (born 24.07.2000). Excluding my programming languages, I speak 8 languages fluently and a couple of others less fluently. Besides constantly learning new things, I love to travel to utilize my skills. I have around five years of experience in various positions.

## **Work Experience**

2020 - Present **Ph.D. Candidate**, Friedrich Miescher Institute for Biomedical Research, Basel, CH.

Writing of my Ph.D. thesis based on where I left off during my Master's.

2018 - 2020 Master's Student, Friedrich Miescher Institute for Biomedical Research, Basel, CH.

- Master thesis project titled "Investigating the stress granule protein G3BP1 with single-molecule imaging of mRNA.". Thesis can be viewed here.
- o As side-project developed an interactive, deep-learning-based, image analysis platform called Fluffy.
- 2018 Research Assistant, Albert Ludwig University of Freiburg, Freiburg im Brsg., DE.
  - o Research work after my Bachelor thesis in the Baumeister laboratory.
  - o Main focus on molecular genetics with Caenorhabditis elegans.
- 2017 Present Sacristan, RKK Oberwil, Oberwil, CH.
  - o Preparation and lecturing during of all kinds of masses including funerals, baptisms etc.
  - o Supervision of around 60 altar servers including home page administration and a monthly work plan.
  - 2016 2019 **Curling Instructor**, Curlingzentrum Region Basel, Arlseheim, CH.
    - o Regular instruction of groups introducing them to the sport of curling in various languages.
    - o Instructions for occasions such as corporate events, birthdays and school excursions.
  - 2016 2019 **Tour Guide**, *NAZ Feldberg*, Feldberg, DE.
    - o Traineeship in environmental education and management of the nature reserve.
    - o Guiding different types of tours and courses for German and French speaking school children.

### Education

2020 - Present **Ph.D. in Cellular Biology**, University of Basel, Basel, CH.

2018 - 2020 MSc in Molecular Biology, University of Basel, Basel, CH.

2015 – 2018 BSc in Biology, Albert Ludwig University of Freiburg, Freiburg im Brsg., DE.

2014 – 2015 **BSc in Chemistry**, *Albert Ludwig University of Freiburg*, Freiburg im Brsg., DE.

Discontinued due to legal age restriction regarding laboratory work. \\

### Abilities

Scientific *C. elegans* methods, Confocal fluorescence microscopy, Fluorescent in-situ hybridization, Image analysis, Lentiviral transfections, Mammalian tissue culture methods, Plasmid design and construction, qPCR, RNA and protein immunoprecipitation, Western blotting.

Programming o Data Science - Deep learning with TF2.x, Image analysis.

- Web development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue, Flask.
- o Unix Comfortable in Vim, Bash.
- Languages o Fluent Swiss German / German, English, Spanish, French, Italian, Portuguese, Norwegian.
  - o Limited Chinese, Japanese.
- Extracuricular o Active duty firefighter Oberwil BL, Corporal
  - o First responder Basel BS
  - Swimming with lifequard certification SLRG